Now that we're done with message
integrity, we're gonna back and talk about
现在我们已经讲完了信息完整性 接下来我们将要回过头来讨论加密
encryption, and we're gonna show how to
construct encryption schemes that provide
我们将展示出如何构建一个加密机制
much stronger security guarantees than
what we had before. But first let's do a
使其提供比我们之前见到的加密方案更为强大的安全保障 但是首先让我们
recap of where we are. So in previous
segments, we talked about confidentiality,
简要回顾一下目前的情况 在之前的课程单元中 我们已经讨论了保密性
in particular how to encrypt messages such
that we achieve semantic security against
特别是如何加密信息 使之对选择明文攻击
what's called a chosen plaintext attack.
Now I kept mentioning again and again that
具有语义安全性 现在我一再提到
security against chosen plaintext attacks
only provides security against
对选择明文攻击的安全性 它仅提供了对抗窃听的安全性
eavesdropping. In other words, this only
provides security against adversaries that
换句话说 这仅提供了对抗窃听网路攻击的安全性
listen to network traffic. But don't
actually change any packets, or don't
但实际上并不会改变任何数据包
inject their own packets, and so on. In
this module, our goal is actually to
也不会加入新的数据包 在本章中 我们的目的是
design encryption schemes that are secure
against adversaries that can tamper with
设计加密机制 使之面对篡改特定数据包和
traffic by blocking certain packets, and
injecting other packets and so on. And
伪造数据包来干扰网络的攻击具有安全性
then we also looked at how to provide
message integrity where the message itself
我们也看到了当信息本身不私密的时候
is not confidential. We just want to make
sure that the message is not modified
如何保证信息完整性 我们只想保证信息在传输过程中
while it's en route. And so we talked
about message authentication codes, MAC
没有被修改 我们讨论了信息验证码
algorithms that provide existential
unforgeability against a chosen message
MAC算法对选择消息攻击提供了不可伪造性
attack. In other words, even though the
attacker is able to obtain the MACs on
换句话说 尽管攻击者可以获取
arbitrary messages of his choice, he can't
build MACs for any other messages. And we
他想要的任何MAC信息 他也不能构建MAC中的其他信息
looked at a number of MAC constructions,
in particular CBC MAC, HMAC, a Parallel mac
我们看过了许多MAC结构 比如 CBC MAC, HMAC以及并行MAC结构
construction. And a fast MAC construction
called a Carter-Wegman MAC. In this
有一个快速MAC结构叫做Carter-Wegman MAC
module, we're going to show how to combine
these confidentiality and integrity
在这一章中 我们会展示如何将私密性和完整性机制结合起来
mechanisms to obtain encryption schemes
that are secure against a much, much
以获得能够安全对抗更强大攻击的加密机制
stronger adversary, namely an adversary that
can tamper with traffic while it's in the
比如能够篡改网路中信息量
network, inject its own packets, block
certain packets, and so on. And our goal
加入自己的数据包 封锁特定数据包等等
is basically to insure that even against
such powerful adversaries, we maintain
我们的目标是尽管面对如此强大的敌手
confidentiality. In other words, the
adversary can't learn what the plain text
仍能保证私密性 换句话说 攻击者无法获得明文内容
is and the adversary can't even modify the
cipher text. And cause the recipient to
也不能篡改密文内容使接收方
think a different plain text was actually
sent. So before we do that I want to give
对修改过的明文信以为真 在那之前我想
you a few examples of adversaries that can
tamper with traffic. And as a result
给出几个能够干扰网络的攻击者的例子
completely break security of CPA secure
encryption. This will show you that,
他们完全破坏了CPA安全加密的安全性 这说明
actually, with that providing integrity,
confidentiality can also be destroyed. In
事实上 尽管那种方法提供了完整性 私密性依然可以被破坏
other words, the two must go together,
integrity and confidentiality, if we're
换句话说 如果我们需要面对主动攻击具有安全性的话
going to achieve security against active
adversaries. So let's look at an example
完整性和私密性缺一不可 让我们看一个来自
from the word of networking. In
particular, let's look at TCP/IP. I'm gonna
网络领域的例子 特别地 让我们看一下TCP/IP
use a highly simplified version of TCP/IP
just so we can quickly focus on the attack
我将使用一个高度简化TCP/IP的模型 这样我们可以快速地定位攻击
and not get bogged down by the details. So
here we have two machines communicating
而不至陷入细枝末节中 我们有两台相互通信的机器
with one another. A user sits at one
machine, and the other machine is a
一台机器被用户使用 另一台是服务器
server. Now, the server, of course, has a
TCP/IP stack that's receiving packets. And
当然 服务器端有一个TCP/IP协议栈 能够接收数据包
then, based on the destination field in
those packets, it forwards the packets to
然后 根据那些数据包的目标地址域 它将这些包发往
the appropriate place. So here we have,
for example, two processes listening to
合适的地址 所以 比如说 在这我们有两个进程在监听
these packets. A web server, say, over
here, and another user, we'll call him
这些数据包 一个叫做web服务器 在这 另一个是用户 我们叫他Bob
Bob, over here. The web server listens on
port 80, and here, this user Bob, listens
在这 web服务器在80端口监听 然后在这  用户Bob
on port 25. Now, when a packet comes in,
the TCP/IP stack looks at the destination
在25端口监听 现在 当一个数据包到来时TCP/IP协议栈查看目标端口
port. In this case, it would be
destination 80, and as a result, the stack
在这个例子里 数据包的目的地是80端口 因此协议栈
forwards the packets over to the web
server. If the destination port said port
将这个包发往web服务器 如果目标端口是25
25, the TCP/IP stack would forward the
packet over to Bob, who's listening on
那么TCP/IP协议栈将会把这个包发给Bob 他正在
port 25. Now, a fairly well known security
protocol called IPsec, encrypts these IP
25端口监听 有一个广为人知的安全协议叫做IPsec 它加密
packets between the sender and the
recipient. So here, the sender and the
发送方和接收方之间的IP数据包 在这 发送方
recipients basically have a shared key.
And when the sender sends IP packets,
和接收方使用共享密钥 当发送方发送IP数据包时
those IP packets are encrypted using the
secret key K. Now when a packet arrives at
这些IP数据包被私密密钥K加密 当一个数据包到达
the destination, and I mean it arrives at
the server, the TCP/IP stack will go ahead
目的地时 我是说它到达服务器 TCP/IP协议栈会
and decrypt the packet, and then look at
the destination port and send it to the
解密这个包 并查看目标端然后将它送往
appropriate place decrypted. You notice
the data here is decrypted. So in this
解密后得到的正确地点 你会注意到这里的数据是被加密了的
case it would send it to the webserver
because the destination port is port 80.
所以在这种情况下 它将会被送往web服务器 因为它的目标端口是80端口
If the destination port happens to be port
25, the TCP/IP stack will decrypt the
如果目标端口恰好是25端口 TCP/IP协议栈会解密数据包
packet, look at the destination port, and
send the data in the clear to the process
查看目标端口 然后将明文数据发送到
who's listening on port 25. So now I wanna
show you that without integrity, in this
正在监听25端口的进程 现在我想向你们展示的是 在这个建立过程中 如果没有完整性
setup, we can't possibly achieve any form
of confidentiality and let's see why. So
我们不可能获得任何形式的保密性 让我们来看看为什么
imagine the attacker intercepts a certain
packet that's intended for the web server.
假设有一个攻击者窃听了一个将要发往web服务器的特定数据包
In other words, it's an encrypted packet
intended for port 80. Remember that the
换句话说 就是一个将要发往80端口的加密数据包
attacker can actually receive the
decryption of any packets that's intended
记住攻击者实际上可以接收到任何发往25端口的解密数据包
for port 25 because the TCP stack will
happily decrypt packets for port 25 and
因为TCP栈会乐意为25端口解密数据包
send them over to Bob who's listening over
here. So what Bob is going to do, Bob here
并把它们发往正在此处监听的Bob Bob作为一个攻击者将
is the attacker, what he's going to do is
he's gonna intercept this packet en route,
将要做的是 将截获网络上的这个数据包
prevent the packet from reaching the
server as is, and instead, he's going to
阻止它到达原本的目标服务器 并且他将会
modify the packet. So now the destination
port is going to read like port 25. This
修改这个数据包 所以现在目标端口将会是25端口
is done on the cipher text and we're going
to see how to do that in just a minute.
这会在密文上完成 我们稍后将看到如何很快的做到这件事
When this packet now arrives at the
server, the destination port says 25, the
当这个数据包现在到达服务器的时候 目标端口是25
server will decrypt the packet, see that
the destination is 25 and forward the data
服务器会解密数据包 看到目标端口是25 然后将数据发给Bob
over to Bob. So now Bob was simply by
changing the destination ports, Bob was
所以现在Bob仅通过修改目标端口
able to read data that was not intended
for himself, but rather was intended for
就能够读取原本不是发给他而是web服务器的数据
the web server. So, if the data is
encrypted using a CBC encryption with a
如果数据是由带随机变量的CBC加密的话
random IV, remember this is a CPA secure
scheme. Nevertheless if that's the case,
记住这是一个CPA安全机制  不过如果情况是这样的话
I'm gonna show you that it's trivial for
the attacker to change the decipher text.
我将向你们展示 攻击者能够很容易地修改密文
So that now he can obtain new cipher text
where the destination port is 25 instead
然后获得目标端口是25而不是80的新密文
of 80. The only thing that's gonna change
is just the IV field. In fact, everything
他所做的只不过是改变变量的域 事实上 其他的一切
else is gonna remain the same. So, let's
see how to do it. So here, just to remind
都会保持原样 让我们看到这是如何做到底 记住
yourself, that, in fact, what the attacker
captured is a CBC encrypted packet. Where
事实上 攻击者截获的是一个CBC加密包
he knows that the destination port is port
80, but he doesn't know what the data is.
他知道其目标端口是80端口 但是不知道数据是什么
The attacker has no clue what the data is
but he does know that his packet is
但是他知道这个数据包是要发往web服务器的
intended for the web server. His goal is
to build a new encrypted packet where now
他的目标是建立一个新的
the destination port is port 25. So the
way he's gonna do is as we said is just by
目标端口为25的加密包。所以他要做的就是
changing the IV, and let me remind you that
the way you decrypt CBC encrypted data is
改变自变量，正如我们之前所说 再让我提醒你一下 解密由CBC加密的数据的方法
essentially the first plain text block is
simply decryption of the first cipher
第一个明文分组实际就是第一个密文分组和
text block XORed with IV. And we
know that in the original packet this is
自变量异或得来的。并且我们还知道原始数据包中
gonna read dest equals 80. Cuz in the
original packet the destination port is
读入的目标端口是80。因为在原始数据包中的目标端口是80。
port 80. So now my question to you is how
will the attacker have changed the IV so
所以我给你的问题就是，攻击者是如何改变自变量才让
now the destination port will read dest
equals 25. So it's pretty easy to see that
读入的目标端口为25。显而易见，
if the attacker simply takes the original
IV, XORs it with here, there are a bunch
如果攻击者使用原始自变量，用这个来异或它，这里有
of zeros over here, and a bunch of zeros
over here. He's XORs it with the zeros,
大串的0,并且这里也有大串的0。他会用这些0来异或这个原始自变量，
and then 80 XORs with zeros, and then 25,
in the appropriate place. Namely, in the
用这些0来异或80以及25。说的就是
port's bytes in the encrypted packets. Then
it's easy to see that when this new IV prime
这些端口加密包中的字节。那这就很容易看出来什么时候
is sent along with the original
cipher text, when the attacker decrypts,
这个新的自变量会随着原始密码文本被发送，什么时候攻击者会解密。
you can see that the original cipher text
would decrypt to port 80, but now the new
你可以看到原始密码文本将会被解密到80端口，但是新的自变量
IV will cancel out this 80, this 80 here
cancels out the 80 that would be obtained
将会取消80，取消了在原始文本中的80
in the original plain text and then by
XORing with 25, essentially the
然后再和25异或。实际上，目标端口现在
destination now becomes 25. So this is a
nice example, where with the simple change
变成了25。这有一个简单的例子，通过简单的改变自变量的域，
to the IV field, the attacker was able to
divert the packet. So that now, after
攻击者可以转移数据包，那么解密之后，
decryption, the packet goes to the
attacker, instead of the actual web
数据包将会传送给攻击者，而不是真正的网络服务器。
server. And as a result now the attacker
can read the plaintext data, that was
结果就是攻击者可以直接读取本应传递给服务器的明文数据。
intended for the server. So this nice
example shows that without integrity it's
这个简单的例子显示如果不具备完整性，
simply impossible for a CPA secure
encryption to provide confidentiality,
那么CPA安全加密所提供的机密性在攻击者可以修改
when the attacker can modify packets
en route. CPA secure encryption only
线路中的数据包时，就只是一纸空文。CPA安全加密仅在
provides confidentiality if the attacker is
only eavesdropping on data, but can't
攻击者只能窃听数据而不能修改线路中的数据的情况下
actually modify a cipher text en route.
Where, as you see, if you can modify
才能保证安全性。好吧你可以看到，如果你也可以修改密文数据，
cipher text, a simple modification,
completely reveals the plaintext. I want
只是一个很小的改动，就可以完全得到明文数据。
to show you another tampering attack that
only requires network access to traffic.
我来向你们展示另一个只需要接入网络的干预型攻击。
It doesn't actually require the attacker
to be present on the decryption machine.
实际上，它不需要攻击者处于解密机器上。
So let's look at an example where there's
a remote terminal application, where every
让我们来看这里的一个远程终端应用的例子。
time the user hits a keystroke, basically
an encrypted keystroke is sent over to the
每一次使用者敲击键盘时，都会把敲击的数据发送给服务器，
server, and let's pretend that the
encrypted keystroke is encrypted using
我们假设键盘输入是用反模式加密的。
counter mode. So here you have the
TCP/IP packet. D here corresponds to the
这里你有一个TCP/IP包，D这里对应键盘输入的一个字节。
one byte keystroke. And as we said, it's
encrypted using counter mode, and as you
正如我们所说，它使用反模式来加密的。
probably know every TCP/IP packet actually
contains a checksum. This is a sixteen bit
你们也许还记得，每一个TCP/IP包都包含一个校验码。
checksum that's just used to detect
transmission errors. So, the server, if it
这个16位的校验码用来检查传输错误。假如，
receives a packet that has the wrong
checksum, it simply drops it on the floor
这个服务器收到含有一个错误的校验码的包，服务器可能
and ignores it. Now the TCP header
including the checksum in the keystroke,
只是简单的丢弃它。现在这个键盘输入的TCP报文头里包含了这个校验码，
all are encrypted using counter mode. Now
the attacker wants to learn what the
并且所有都是反模式加密，现在攻击者先要得知键盘输入的是什么
keystroke was, and let me show you what he
can do. The attacker is gonna intercept
让我告诉你们他会怎么做。攻击者会截获这个数据包
this packet and he's not actually gonna
modify it, he's gonna send it over to the
并不打算修改它，他要先把数据包发送到服务器。
server. But he's gonna record the packet.
Later on he's gonna modify the packet and
但是攻击者会先记录这个包。稍后，他就会修改包，然后
send a modified packet over to the server.
What he's going to do is he's gonna XOR
把修改后的包再发送给服务器。他要做的就是要把
the encrypted checksum field with a
value T and he's going to XOR the
加密的校验码空间与T进行异或，然后再用
encrypted data field with a value S. And
he's going to do this for lots and lots of
加密数据空间和S进行异或。他会用大量的T和S来做这项工作。
T and S. Now remember, a property
of counter mode is that if you XOR the
记住，反模式加密的一个性质就是，如果你用解密后的T和密文进行异或
cipher text with T after decryption, the
result in plain text is also XOR with T.
结果就是明文也要和T异或
Similarly, if You XOR the encrypted data with s after decryption.
同理，如果你用解密过的S和加密数据进行异或，
the resulting decrypted data will also be
encrypted with s. Now, the server's gonna
得出的解密数据也要和加密的S进行异或。
decrypt this modified packet. And the
resulting packet is gonna have the
现在，服务器要解密这个被修改的包，得出的包中的
check sum XORed with t, and the data XORed with s. Now what happens if the
校验码要和T进行异或，数据要和S进行异或。
modified check sum is correct for this
modified packet, the server will send an
那么如果被修改包中的校验码是正确的，服务器就会发出一份回复
ACK back. If the modified check sum
is incorrect for this modified packet, the
如果被修改包中的校验码是错误的，服务器就会
server will just drop the packet on the
floor and do nothing. So the attacker can
丢掉这个包，然后什么也不做。所以，
simply observe, look for an ACK packet or
not, and in doing so, he learns whether
攻击者就只观察，看有没有回复的ACK包。这样他就
this particular XOR of T and XOR of S
pairs corresponds to a valid checksum or not.
可以得知，这个特殊的T异或和S异或对是否对应一个真正的校验码
Now the attacker's going to do
this for lots and lots of T's and S's.
攻击者会使用大量的T和S来重复这样做。
And you notice what he learns is if I
modify the data by XORing it with this
你会注意到，他用特殊值S异或数据来修改数据，
particular value S, that changes the
checksum by a particular value T. And
用特殊值T异或校验码来修改校验码。
he learns this for lots and lots of T and
S pairs. So it turns out for certain
并且他这样做用很多很多的T、S对。所以
checksums, by looking at a sequence of
equations of this type. You can actually
通过查找一系列这种形式的方程，你可以得到一个确定的校验码。
figure out what the value D is. I should
point out that for the TCP checksums on this,
这样就可以算出D的值是多少了。我想要说的是，
actually, might not be true, But
certainly, they're easy checksums for
通过这种办法算出的TCP的校验码可能是不正确的。但要算出正确的
which this is actually absolutely true. So
again by looking at a lot of equations of
校验码还是很容易的。所以通过大量的这种类型的等式
this type the attacker can recover D. And
this is a really nice example of what's
攻击者就可以发现D。这里有一个非常好的例子
called a chosen cipher text attack. The
attacker basically submitted cipher text
叫做选择密文攻击。攻击者通常从
of his choice that was derived from that
cipher text that he wanted to decrypt. And
他想要破解的密文中选择提取一部分
then by looking at how the server
responded he was able to learn something
然后通过服务器的回应来得知
about the resulting plaint text. And by
repeating this for many different values
可能的明文。然后用大量不同的T和S重复这一过程，
of T and S he was actually eventually able to
recover what the actual full plain text is.
他最终可以发现他想要的全部明文是什么。
So in this segment we are gonna look
at many more examples of attacks of this
那么这一小节中，我们将看到更多这种攻击的例子。
type. These are called active attacks,
where the attackers actually modify
它们都叫做主动攻击，因为攻击者通常会修改通信量。
traffic in route. And I hope that these
two simple example convinces you that all
我希望这两个例子可以使你们相信
you provide is CPA security other words
security against eavesdropping. You can't
CPA的安全性只能应对窃听，但是面对主动攻击
even guarantee secrecy against an active
attacker. Not only does your cipher text
不能保证安全性。
not have integrity, in other words the
recipients might obtain a message
不仅仅是密文不具有完整性，就是说
different from the one sent by the sender.
But you don't even have confidentiality.
发送方发送的消息和接受方获得的不一致，而且这种密码甚至也不具有保密性。
And I showed you two examples where
without integrity the attacker can simply
并且我也给你们展示了两个不具备完整性的例子，告诉你们
decrypt the packet by using the recipient
as an oracle for decrypting certain parts
攻击者可以使用收到的包来破解数据。
of the data. And so the lesson that I'm
gonna repeat again and again and again
所以，这部分我一而再再而三的强调的就是，
throughout this module is that if your
message needs integrity but no
如果你想要完整性而不管安全性，就用MAC
confidentiality, just use a MAC. But if
your message needs integrity and
但是如果你既需要完整性也需要安全性的话，
confidentiality, you have to use what's
called an authenticated encryption mode,
你就需要使用认证加密机制，
which is precisely the topic of this
module. So the next thing we're gonna do
这恰好也是我们这个模块的主题。所以，我们接下来要做的
is define what authenticated encryption
means. And we're gonna build authenticated
就是定义认证加密的含义，而且我们将构建一个认证加密系统。
encryption systems. But the point I want
you to remember is that the CPA security
但是我还想提醒下你们的就是CPA安全机制
modes we discussed before should never
actually be used to encrypt data by
不应该只通过他们自己来加密数据。
themselves. So CBC with a random IV is a
building block towards authenticated
所以，带有一个随机自变量的CBC就是朝着认证加密靠进
encryption, but should never be used on
its own. Okay. So we're gonna define
的一款分组密码。但是也不应该单独使用。好吧，我们将会在
authenticated encryption in the next
segment.
下一小节中解释认证加密。